Archit Vishnoi

Portfolio: https://v-archit.github.io

Mobile: +1 (585) 553 - 6637 | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/archit-vishnoi | Email: av1567@rit.edu

Summary

M.S. Game Design Development student with 3 years' experience in Unity Application Development with C#. Extensive work on VR and AR platform using SteamVR, Vuforia, and ARCore. Interested in Gameplay, AI, and Graphics Programming. Seeking to leverage this experience and skills gained to contribute to a Full-time position / Internship for Summer/Fall '23. Talk to me about Valorant, Witcher 3, Firewatch, and Thief 2.

Education

M.S. Game Design Development (3.8/4.0 GPA)

(Aug 2021 - May 2023)

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

• Key coursework: Game Development Process, Engine and Graphics Programming, and Al.

B.Tech. Computer Science Engineering (7.2/10.0 CGPA)

(Aug 2014 – May 2018)

Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida

Experience

Vizara Technologies Pvt Ltd, Gurugram

(May 2019 - Jun 2021)

Computer Graphics Engineer

- Worked on Unity with C# scripting, Visual Studio, .NET framework, Room-scale tracking with SteamVR, Image/Model Recognition AR apps using Vuforia, and Google ARCore.
- Represented Vizara in India International Science Fest '18 and Unity Dev Conference '19.

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

(Aug 2018 – Apr 2019)

Junior Research Fellow

• Worked as Unity Developer on the project, 'Digital Mini Spectacle', goal was to create digital installations using 3D laser scan data, AR, Holographic Projections, with special attention to novelty and optimization using VR, AR, and MR solutions.

Projects

Into The Babyverse – 3D Space Shooter Game – Unreal C++

(M.S. 4th Sem)

6 DOF spaceship movement, custom hit-planet physics, Chaos destruction, Al

Hoodwink (Group) - 3D Wild West Action Game - Unreal C++

(M.S. 3rd Sem)

- Responsible for Townsfolk AI with Patrol, Chase, Melee, and Flee behaviors.
- Behavior Trees, BT Tasks, Decorators, Audio-Visual-Touch Perception Graph

The Al Story (Group) - 2D Narrative Game - Unity C# Inky

(M.S. 3rd Sem)

• Responsible for programming, UI, game logic, Inky file management, dialogue system

Smoke Particle System - DirectX HLSL DirectXMath ImGUI

(M.S. 3rd Sem)

• Custom graphics pipeline for basic particles – size, color, velocity, lifetime, recycle pool

Infinite Stars - 2D Game - OpenGL GLFW GLEW GLM ImGUI

(M.S. 2nd Sem)

Custom graphics pipeline, collision detection, gravity sim, play/pause state, camera movement

Season Soiree (Group) - 2D Platformer - Unity C#

(M.S. 2nd Sem)

• Responsible for UI Design, Animations, and Transitions - VFX using Particle System

Tower Defense – 2D Strategy Game – Unity C#

(M.S. 1st Sem)

Goal Oriented Action Planning AI - manage economy, spawn/kill combat, siege, labour units

Food Delivery - 2D Simulation AI - Unity C#

(M.S. 1st Sem)

• Goal Oriented Action Planning AI – inventory, re-stocking, cooking, delivery, best option

Skills

- Technical skills:
 - 3+ Years Unity, C#, C++, Data Structures, 3D Mathematics, Visual Studio, GitHub, Jira
 - 1+ Years Unreal, OpenGL, DirectX, HLSL, Perforce, Trello
- Soft skills:

Interpersonal Communication, Problem-solving, Detail-oriented, Team player, Critical thinking

Extracurricular Activities

- Head Coordinator Graphics and Animation Hub, JIIT Noida
- (Aug 2016 May 2018)
- o Organized the Game Development Hackathon in Cybersrishti 2017 College Tech Fest.
- o Taught in Unity Game Development and Photoshop Workshop in JIIT Noida in 2018.